ILGWU Local 62 Records 5780/021
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 62 Records
1913-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 62
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/021
4 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records.
The collection contains minutes of Local 62's Executive Board's meetings between 1913 and 1971, as well as issues of the local's publication, Our Union, from 1935 to 1970.
5490742
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, September 26, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The White Goods Workers' Union Local 62, also known as the Underwear and White Goods Workers Union, was chartered in 1909, but was not fully organized until 1913. Rose Schneiderman and the Women's Trade Union League assisted with the early organizing efforts of the White Goods Workers. These workers consisted mainly of young immigrant girls. Early leaders of the local included Samuel Shore. On March 1913, 15,000 workers went on strike against the sweatshop conditions. A six week strike ensued in which many of the girls on the picket lines were attacked and arrested. Gains won included a 54 hour week, no Sunday, sanitary conditions and an 18 cent an hour minimum wage. This strike made the local.
The local and its workers were originally called white goods workers as they manufactured camisoles, chemises, cambric drawers with lace ruffles and drawstrings, and corset covers. Through the years, styles changed and production shifted to panties and slips. In the 1960s, the local became the Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union Local 62.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains minutes of Local 62's Executive Board's meetings, as well as issues of the local's publication, "Our Union," from 1935 to 1970. The earliest minutes of the Executive Board of Local 62 date to 1913 and run until 1971. These bound meeting minutes are in Yiddish. Later copies of minutes were bound with reports and financial statements.
"Our Union" was the official publication of the local that began in February 1935. The bulletin was printed monthly and includes information on the industry, agreements, education, recreation, and culture. Later years include a section in Spanish.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/022: ILGWU Local 62 Correspondence 5780/074: ILGWU Mary Goff Schuster Papers 5780/079: ILGWU Local 62 Managers' Correspondence 5780/089: ILGWU Local 62-32 Agreements
Arrangement
Series I: Executive Board Minutes, 1913-1971
Series II: Our Union. Periodical, 1935-1970
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 62 (New York, N.Y.)
5490742
- Series Series I: Executive Board Minutes, 1913-1971
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Yiddish
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1915-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1923-1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Yiddish. Fragile
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Our Union" Vol. XXII, No.1-Vol.XXII, No.37, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board Minutes., 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series Series II: Our Union. Periodical, 1935-1970
  - "Our Union" Vol.I, No.1- Vol. VIII, No.12, 1935-1941 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Our Union" Vol. IX No.1- Vol. XII, No.10, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Our Union" Vol. XII, No.11-Vol.XIII, No.17, 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Our Union", No.11-Vol.XIII, No.17 [copy 2], 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Our Union", No.18-Vol.XV, No.14, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Our Union", No.18-Vol.XV, No.14 [copy 2], 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Our Union", No.18-Vol.XV, No.14 [copy 3], 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Our Union" Vol. XVI, No.1-Vol XVII, No.12, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Our Union" Vol. XVI, No.1-Vol.XVII, No.12 [copy 2], 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Our Union" Vol. XVIII, No.1-Vol.XIX, No.8, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Our Union" Vol. XVIII, No.1-Vol.XIX, No.8 [copy 2], 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Our Union" Vol. XIX, No.9- Vol. XXI, No.10, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 15)